EVRARD RODRIGUEZ MARCEL

Frontend Developer | React | Vue.js | JavaScript

Phone @ Evrardrodrigue3@gmail.com

Attps://evrard-portfolio-0304.netlify.app/ Strasburg, France

SUMMARY

Evrard is a senior frontend developer with over 20 years of experience. He has worked in the IT industry for about 25 years.

Evrard focuses on React and modern JavaScript/TypeScript frameworks and has spent time in full-stack roles using Node.is servers for top-tier international companies. With his fantastic communication and leadership skills, he has led teams with 2-10 developers. His most attractive attribute is his attention to detail, followed closely by his demand for quality. Evrard has significant experience working in the fashion and beauty industry, as well as with fintech companies.

Evrard is expertise in:

- -React Native: 7+ years of experience
- -Vue.js: 5+ years of experience
- -Javascript
- -Typescript
- -Redux
- -Tailwind Css

Throughout my career, I have successfully completed multiple projects, contributing to both startups and established companies. I thrive in fast-paced environments and enjoy tackling complex challenges.

I am excited about the opportunity to use my skills to help businesses grow and succeed through innovative web solutions. Let's connect and discuss how I can contribute to your next project!

EXPERIENCE

Front-end Developer

09/2022 - 09/2024 Strasburg, France

Dassault Systèmes

Company Description

· Provided front-end feature updates as required for an existing AngularJS administration application.

- Worked on a small agile team to take over ownership of an existing internal React component library. Provided updates and bug fixes as requested by internal teams.
- Migrated the React component library project to a new packaging and deployment strategy using Nx and Rollup, a module bundler for JavaScript which compiles small pieces of code into something larger and more complex, such as a library or application.
- Converted the existing codebase of the React component library to TypeScript.

Lead Front-end Developer

03/2020 - 09/2022 Strasburg, France

Capgemini

Company Description

- Created an internal B2B eCommerce application for iOS using React Native.
- · Created a user storage application using React and Node.js; implemented Express server to use as middleware to third-party services.
- · Implemented company-wide standard coding practices using custom ESLint configuration and Husky.



KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

Tour Achievement

Describe what you did and the impact it had.

SKILLS

React

Redux

Vue.js

JavaScript

TypeScript

Tailwind CSS

HTML

CSS

Node.js

MongoDB

COURSES

Course Title

PASSIONS



Career Interest / Passion

EXPERIENCE

React and Node.js Software Engineer

01/2019 - 03/2020

BlaBlaCar

Strasburg, France

Company Description

- Worked on a high-traffic software reviews collection site developed with React, AWS Lambda, Elasticsearch, Ruby on Rails, and DynomoDB.
- Monitored error logs daily and did performance tracking, documenting and prioritizing errors and performance issues.
- Created and implemented an initiative to refactor all existing code, from using complicated callback code to using promises and async/await syntax. Significantly simplified the code and improved error handling.
- Enhanced error handling for the application and improved error logging with stack trace detailing to rollbar logs to significantly improve the team's ability to recognize and resolve bugs and performance issues quickly.
- Created Elasticsearch indexes as required for our project from company data and Kafka topics created for our consumption.
- Was involved in grooming new features from the product team and suggesting effective, performant technical implementation solutions.
- Filled in for the lead engineer for six weeks, managing two new developers and successfully leading the team to complete two main features on time.
- · Involved in the migration that leveraged Next.js.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science (BS), Computer science

09/2014 - 09/2019

Université de Paris

LANGUAGES

English Native •••• French Native ••••

